准备好了吗  孩子们
Are you ready, kids?
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
我听不见
I can't hear you
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
是谁住在深海的大菠萝里
Who lives in a pineapple under the sea?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
方方黄黄伸缩自如
Absorbent and yellow and porous is he
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
如果四处探险是你的愿望
If nautical nonsense be something you wish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
那就敲敲甲板让大鱼开路
Then drop on the deck and flop like a fish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
准备
Ready
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
奶奶的吻
导演
翻译: 1440kHz
分镜总监
编剧
动画总监
创意总监
客串
配音 海绵奶奶
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
就是这了
There it is
奶奶的家
Grandma's house
今天会有什么好东西在等着我呢
What wonders await me today
新鲜现烤的饼干
Fresh-baked cookies?
故事时间
Story time?
每一针都充满爱的毛衣
A sweater with love in every stitch?
我还等什么呢
What am I waiting for?
奶奶
Grandma
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
奶奶好
Hi, Grandma
快进来坐一会吧
Come in and sit for a while
来吃饼干  海绵宝宝
Have a cookie, SpongeBob
奶奶  你做的饼干是全海洋最棒的了
Grandma, you make the best cookies
in the deep blue sea
好啊
Oh, yeah
奶奶的饼干
Grandma's cookies
有谁想要舔勺子呢
Now, who wants to lick the spoon?
我我我
Me, me, me
然后我们一路开回了家
And then we drove all the way home
没关车窗  在这大冷天里飞驰着
with all the windows down in the freezing cold
再跟我讲个我小时候的故事吧
Tell me another story about when I was a baby
三点了
3:00
我上班要迟到了
I'm going to be late for work
来坐我的车
Hop in my car
我送你过去
I'll drop you off
蟹堡王
谢谢奶奶
Thanks, Grandma
入口
海绵宝宝  你忘了要亲亲了
SpongeBob, you forgot your kissy-kissy
确实是
I sure did
奶奶拜拜
Bye, Grandma
谢谢你送我
Thanks for the ride
谢谢章鱼哥
Thank you, Squidward
天啊
Oh, brother
是不是很棒啊
Isn't this great?
大家今天的心情真不错
Everybody's in a good mood today
我很想过来煞风景  海绵宝宝
I love bursting your bubble, SpongeBob
他们这是在笑你  不是在跟你笑
They're laughing at you, not with you
我做了什么可笑的事吗
Did I do something funny?
看你额头
Your forehead
我额头可笑吗
My forehead is funny?
奶奶的小宝贝
Hey, grandma's boy
亲亲亲亲亲亲
Kissy-kissy-kissy
不
No
你们都错了
You're wrong
被
There
被奶奶亲没什么大不了的
there's nothing wrong
with getting kisses from your grandma
可不是嘛
No
要是你是个穿纸尿裤的巨婴就更对了
especially if you're a big baby who wears diapers
还吸大拇指
And, and sucks his thumb
玩布娃娃
and plays with dolls
还
and, um
穿着长得让脚都伸不出的睡衣
wears pajamas with feet in them
还带着
and carries his, um
小毯毯到处跑  还
binky around, and, uh
差不多得了
All right already
振作点  海绵宝宝
Cheer up, SpongeBob
我知道还有个喜欢你的人
I know someone who still likes you
真的吗
Really?
你真知道吗  章鱼哥
You do, Squidward?
对
Yeah
就是你奶奶
Your grandma
住口
Stop it
我再也不要在大庭广众之下受辱了
I have been publicly humiliated for the last time
我为你之前的事情难过  海绵宝宝
I'm sorry that happened to you, SpongeBob
我也是
Me, too
你是我认识的最大人的人了
You're the most adult person I know
谢了  派大星
Thanks, Patrick
你要知道奶奶都是些什么货色
You know how grandmas are
她们爱小宝宝
They love babies
你就不能在她身边表现得像个小宝宝
You just can't act like a baby around her
说得对  派大星
You're right, Patrick
我什么时候没对过
Have I ever not been right?
你现在是男子汉了  海绵宝宝
You're a man now, SpongeBob
你是时候该表现得像个男子汉了
and it's time you started acting like one
对
Yeah
可我不太确定要怎么表现
But I'm not sure I know how
让我来演示
Allow me to demonstrate
首先  挺起胸膛
First, puff out your chest
现在说  免除税款
Now say "tax exemption”
免除税款
Tax exemption
现在你必须学会品味自由爵士乐
Now you must acquire a taste for free-form jazz
行了  海绵宝宝
Okay, SpongeBob
你准备好了
You're ready
就这样了
This is it
你要跟你奶奶说什么
What are you going to tell Grandma?
我是个大人
I'm a grown-up
对此不准有任何异议
No ifs, ands or buts about it
男子汉要做男子汉要做的事
A man's got to do what a man's got to do
然后你就到她身后  我来推一把
And then you get behind her and I'll push
派大星  这可不在计划内
Patrick, we didn't say that
没错  确实
Oh yeah, right
现在就只缺成年礼蛋糕上的糖霜了
All we need now is the icing on the maturity cake
好几年来我一直在养着这些小宝贝
I've been growing these babies for years
络腮胡子
Sideburns
你好  海绵宝宝
Hello, SpongeBob
多么惊喜啊
What a nice surprise
过来吧  让奶奶给你亲亲
Come here, give your granny her kissy-kissy
抱歉  祖母
Sorry, Grandmother
不能再亲下去了
but the kissing has to stop
就这样跟她说  海绵宝宝
Tell her like it is, SpongeBob
不要搞幼稚了
No more baby stuff
他说得对  祖母
He is right, Grandmother
亲亲是给小宝宝的  而我不再是了
Kisses are for babies, which I am no longer
我已经长大了
I have grown up
这是自然之道
It is nature's way
你说得对极了
You are absolutely right
有吗
I am?
我是说  我说得当然对
I mean, of course I am
你在这绝对再也不会被当成小宝宝了
You will definitely not be treated
like a baby around here ever again
很高兴你从我的角度看问题  祖母
I am glad you see it my way, Grandmother
那我很高兴看到事情办妥了
Well, I'm glad that's settled
可我又要怎么处理
But what am I going to do
这些新鲜现烤的饼干呢
with all these fresh-baked cookies
对不起  祖母
Sorry, Grandmother
我们大人是不摄取甜食的
We adults don't partake in the consumption of sweets
对吧  派
Right, Pat
大星
rick?
多来点  奶奶
Keep 'em coming, Granny
不搞幼稚这套不过如此
So much for no more baby stuff
别忘了戴吃饼干专用帽哦
And don't forget the cookie-eating hat
那顶吃饼干专用帽是我的
That's my cookie-eating hat
我是说  是我小时候的
I mean, it was when I was a baby
看看谁来了
Well, look who's here
是我的老大人孙子
It's my big old adult grandson
祖母  我要和派大星来场成熟的对话
Grandmother, I need to have a mature conversation
with Mr. Patrick
派大星
Patrick
你在做什么
What are you doing?
饼干
Cookies
热牛奶
Warm milk
我爱奶奶
围兜
A bib
你额头上的是不是唇印
Is that a kissy mark on your forehead?
我们应该是要当大人的
We are supposed to be adults
吃饱了不要打闹哦
No roughhousing with a full tummy
谁是小宝宝
Who's the baby?
我是小宝宝
I'm the baby
当大人也太没意思了
Being grownup is boring
我爱当小宝宝
I love being a baby
并且我也听不懂爵士
Besides, I don't get jazz
可怜的派大星
Poor Patrick
我都快为你感到难过了
I almost feel sorry for you
困在穿尿布的尴尬时期
Trapped in the awkward phase of diaper days
无法理解当大人收获的丰厚回报
Never to know the rich rewards of being a grownup
一批新鲜现烤的饼干来了
Here's a fresh batch of cookies
那好
All right
回报是吧
Rewards, huh?
对  有
Well, yeah, there's
我想想  我们
Let's see, we, uh
我们听了爵士
we went over the jazz
奶奶  我吃饱了
Grandma, I'm full
还有饼干哦
More cookies
我的午餐时间也到了
It appears to be my lunch hour
大人也必须吃饭
Grownups have to eat, too
看来只能吃这个了
I guess this will have to do
你可不想吃这小宝宝吃的玩意
You don't want this baby food
这一大块的蒸珊瑚怎么样
How about a big piece of steamed coral?
好
Oh, yeah
太棒了
Great
太营养了
Nutritious
故事时间到
Story time
天啊
Oh, boy
故事时间
Story time
Story time?
你会喜欢的  派大星
You'll enjoy this Patrick
这精彩的故事讲的是一只神奇的海妖
It's a wonderful story about a magical sea leprechaun
海绵宝宝  你肯定没兴趣听这宝宝书
SpongeBob, you wouldn't be interested in this babybook
这是关于常规保养的技术手册
Here's the technical manual
on Routine Active Maintenance
好棒
Great
嗯
Yeah
引人入胜
Fascinating
没有插图  我就喜欢这样
No pictures, just the way I like it
我的小指指
My wittle finger
别乱动  别乱动
Hold still, hold still
好了点没
All better?
一点点
Sorta
这根指头也有点疼
This finger hurts a little bit, too
要不要我送你礼物呢
How about I give you a present?
天啊  希望是饼干
Oh, boy, I hope it's cookies
好耶
All right
又一顶帽子
Another hat
不对派大星  这是毛衣
No, Patrick, it's a sweater
每一针都充满了爱
With love in every stitch
不
No
我难道就没有礼物吗  奶奶
Don't I get a present, Grandma?
差点忘了
I almost forgot
给你办公用品
Here's some office supplies
我没做包装
I didn't wrap them
你肯定不会介意的
I knew you wouldn't mind
三点了
3:00
大人该去上班了
Time for adults to go to work
拜拜  海绵宝宝
Bye-bye, SpongeBob
你肯定想睡午觉是不是  派大星
I'll bet you would fancy a nap, huh, Patrick
你还没走吗  海绵宝宝
You're still here, SpongeBob?
我现在还不急着走
I don't have to leave yet
上班迟到也没关系
I can be late for work
不不不
No, no, no
你那样才不是大人做的事
That wouldn't be the adult thing to do
好吧
All right
那我就走了
I guess I'll be going
我
I've, uh
还有好多大人的公务要干
got a lot of adult-type business to take care of
那就
so, uh
再见了
I'll see you later
好
Okay
谢谢你顺路来看我  海绵宝宝
Thanks for stopping by, SpongeBob
好  就这样了
Yup, that is it
我走了
Here I go
有空的话要再回来哦
Come again if you get the chance
进入冷酷的大人世界
Out into the cold grown-up world
孤身一人
alone
没有毛衣
without a sweater
拜拜了
Toodle-oo
不知道我何时才能回来
I don't know when I'll be back
我知道你可忙了
I know how busy you are
那就
So, uh
这样吧
that's it
他睡着了
He's asleep
再见
So long
我不想长大
I don't want to grow up
我想吃饼干
I want cookies
还有喝奶奶
And milky
我想要每一针都充满爱的毛衣
I want a sweater with love in the stitches
我想穿纸尿裤
I want to wear didies
我想骑小车车
I want to ride in my wagon
我想抱抱毛绒玩具小先生
I want to cuddle-wuddle with Mr. Stuffykins
我想坐上海马马摇啊摇
I want to rocky-rock on my seahorsey
我还想要亲亲我的伤口
And I want kissy-kissy on my boo-boo
别哭了  海绵宝宝
Take it easy, SpongeBob
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
你不必依靠变成小宝宝
You don't have to be a baby
来得到奶奶的爱
to get Old Grandma's love
是吗
I don't?
那当然了
Of course not
不管你长得有多大
No matter how grownup you get
你一直都会是我的小小宝宝
you will always be my Little Baby Boo
记好了  你亲亲奶奶的同时
And remember, you can kiss your Grandma
也是可以当大人的
and still be an adult
给你吧
Here you go
谢谢奶奶
Thanks, Grandma
奶奶  问下能不能别
Grandma, could you not mention
跟蟹堡王那些人说这事
this to the guys down at The Krusty Krab?
没问题
No problem
章鱼村
分镜总监
翻译: 1440kHz
分镜
编剧
动画总监
创意总监
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
派大星你看  我收到了
Patrick, look, I got my
对不起  派大星
I'm sorry, Patrick
只是
It's just
我刚还以为
for a second I thought
你买的鼓风机跟我的一个样
You got the same reef-blower as me
抓到了  你当鬼
Tag, you're it
吹
吸
派大星
Patrick
你让我家干净到发亮了
you made my house sparkly clean
那当然
Sure did
还没让章鱼哥也今天开心一下呢
We haven't improved Squidward's day yet
来搞他家吧
Let's do his house
轮到我了
My turn
外面这是怎么了
What's going on out here?
我们在玩新买的鼓风机
We're playing with our new reef-blowers
玩鼓风机
Playing with a reef-blower?
这可是我听过最幼稚的事情了
That is the most childish thing I've ever heard of
可是很好玩的
But it's fun
好玩
Fun?
玩个特大号头发烘干机怎么好玩了
How could playing with one of those
oversized hair dryers possibly be fun?
就像这样
Like this
我生气了
Chafed
擦 伤
好了  都
All right, that's
来整你家吧  派大星
Let's do your house, Patrick
好
Yeah
章鱼哥  你在冒气
Squidward, you're steaming
就跟蒸菜似的  只是聪明点
You're like a steamed vegetable, only smarter
把我窗户放回去
Put my windows back
没问题  章鱼哥
No problem, Squidward
我们挺你
We're on your side
随时都能成
Any second now
海绵宝宝  这是最后底线
SpongeBob, this is the final straw
我要搬到很远的地方去
I am going to move so far away
远到我可以吹的地步
that I will be able to brag about it
我宁
I would
我宁愿把我脑干扒出来
I would rather tear out my brain stem
把它带到最近的十字路口正中央
carry it into the middle of
the nearest four-way intersection
再拿着它跳绳
and skip rope with it
也不住我现在住的这破地方
than go on living where I do now
你好
Hi there
这是最后底线吗
Is this the final straw?
你想要搬到很远的地方去
Do you want to move so far away
远到你可以吹的地步吗
that you can brag about it?
你宁愿把你脑干扒出来
Would you rather tear out your brain stem
走到最近的丁字路口正中央
walk out into the middle of the nearest three-way
是十字
Four-way
十字路口正中央
Four-way intersection
再拿着它跳绳
and skip rope with it
也不继续住你现在住的破地方吗
than continue living where you do now?
那就搬来
Then move to
我讨厌这个频道
I hate this channel
不  不
No, no
章鱼村
Tentacle Acres
在这里  快乐离你只有一吸盘之遥
Where happiness is just a suction cup away
章鱼村
你好
Hello?
请问有什么事
Yes, can I help you?
我是来这享乐的
I'm here about the happiness
我现在要搬进来住
I'll be moving in now
自己一个来的吗
Are you alone?
不
No
我是说  对
I mean, yes
没人跟着我一起来  对
there's nobody with me, yes
宁静祥和
Peace and quiet
你现在或曾经是海绵吗
Are you now or have you ever been a sponge?
不
No
那么还
What about a
不  不是海星
No, no starfish
我就只是个普通正常爱宁静的
Just a regular, normal peace-loving
杏仁糖
小心
总算到天堂了
Heaven at last
我在养老院里见过的人机灵多了
I've seen more alert people in a retirement home
无脑生活研讨会要往哪走
Which way to the Living Without a Brain seminar?
可别迟到了
Don't be late
火鸡三明治都比你会还嘴
I've heard better comebacks from a turkey sandwich
笨 蛋
找点正经事做去
Get a life
这地方比我预想的还要好
This place is better than I expected
然后304
and 304
漂亮
Beautiful
而且一个菠萝都看不到
And not a pineapple in sight
晚安  竖笛
Good night, Clary
明天我们就要开启新生活了
Tomorrow we begin life anew
新生活街304号  我是章鱼哥
304 New Life Street, Squidward speaking
我是不会再搬回去的  海绵宝宝
There is no way I am moving back there, SpongeBob
我总算跟我同类住在一块了
I am finally among my own kind
再见吧你
Now good-bye
今天我要骑自行车
I think I'll take my bike today
我的事情我做主
I'm my own man
这些邻居深谙生活之道
Now, these neighbors know how to live
满溢健康
细致入微
Intensive
他们肯定没有
I bet they won't have
还真有
They have it
罐装面包
切完片
就是好东西
罐装面包
Canned bread
这城好棒
This town is great
我肯定会被惊艳到  如果这地方有
I would really be impressed if it had
形意舞学院
an interpretive dance academy
好啊
Yeah
组团跳舞可更好了
It's even better in a group
这城好完美
This town is perfect
竖笛三重奏
A clarinet trio?
又是美好的一天
Another great day
快看啊
Oh, look
大家今天都在骑车
Everybody's on their bike today
满溢健康
生活变得越来越好了
It just gets better and better
一起来
All together
我今天
I sort of
有点不想吹竖笛了
don't feel like playing my clarinet today
太棒了这是
Yup, this is great
他们怕是得把这城改名叫章鱼哥天堂
They might as well rename this town
Squidward's Paradise
或者可能应该改
Or perhaps
过分的天堂
Too Much Paradise
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob?
随时回来
吸
吹
落叶
Leaves
走 开
清理落叶而已
Just getting the leaves
你能不能小点声  铁肺物
Could you pipe down over there, Iron Lung?
看样子每当找乐子的时候
Looks like when it comes to having fun
你们就站不住脚了
you don't have a leg to stand on
那可不好笑
That's not funny
没错
Yeah
这是怎么了
What's going on over here?
是那家伙
It's that guy
他在玩鼓风机
He's playing with a reef-blower
玩
Playing
鼓风机
With a reef-blower?
这可是我听过最幼稚的事情了
That's the most childish thing I've ever heard of
可是很好玩的
But it's fun
玩个特大号头发烘干机怎么好玩了
How could you possibly have fun
with one of those oversized hair dryers?
就像这样
Like this
快还来
Give it back
求你了
Please
抓到了  你当鬼
Tag, you're it
咖啡厅
我能给你点什么呢
What can I get you boys?
你瞅啥
What are you looking at?
那俩鼻子
Those
章鱼村
我们到了  派大星
Here it is, Patrick
现在要说服章鱼哥回家去
Now we've just got to convince
Squidward to come back home
你带道歉蛋糕了没
You got our apology cake?
对不起
我们准备好了
We're ready
你好  请问有什么事
Hello, can I help you?
我能点一份一号餐  特大份的吗
Can I get a large number one, extra size?
可你刚已经吃了三份炸牡蛎壳了
But you just ate three orders of fried oyster skins
我爱炸牡蛎壳
I love fried oyster skins
大门关闭
很抱歉  你们这类人不得进入
We're sorry, but your kind isn't allowed here
他不走  奥维尔
He's not leaving, Orville
你警棍备好了没
You got your nightstick ready?
炸牡蛎壳
Fried oyster skins?
大门关闭
大门开启
看来只能进去点餐了
I guess we got to order inside
那位看着很像章鱼哥
That looked like Squidward
那位看着很也像章鱼哥
That looked like Squidward also
只是成了暴民
in angry mob form
站在那别动  章鱼哥先生
Hold it right there, Mr. Tentacles
都退后
Stay back
我手上有园艺工具
I got gardening tools
给你看看这个
Here, just read this
什么东西
What is it?
经过深思熟虑精心编排的投诉清单
A well thought-out and organized list of complaints
派大星你看  是章鱼哥
Patrick, look, it's Squidward
章鱼哥
Squidward
总算找到你了
We finally found you
别碰我
Get off me
我不是章鱼哥
I'm not Squidward
你现在是章鱼哥了吗
Are you Squidward now?
委屈
Grievances?
这座城属实让人委屈
This town is a grievance
应该要有项法律
There should be a law
禁止让这么多装小气自大狂
against so many stuck-up tightwads
都住在同一个地方
living in one place
这座城需要被毁掉
This city needs to be destroyed
最起码也要重新粉刷成别的颜色
Or at least painted a different color
提醒你  你没必要住在这知道不
FYI, you don't have to live here, you know
你说得对
You're right
我马上就走
And I'm leaving ASAP
你是章鱼哥吗
Are you Squidward?
不是
No
你是章鱼哥吗
Are you Squidward?
不是
No
你是章鱼哥吗
Are you Squidward?
那行吧  你慢慢来
That's okay, take your time
这些章鱼哥随便哪一个
Any one of these Squidwards
都有可能是真正的章鱼哥
could be the real Squidward, Patrick
自由了
Freedom
至少有件事是清楚的
Well, we know one thing
那位肯定不是章鱼哥
It sure isn't that guy